Congratulations.
お疲れさまでした
You've successfully completed the Udacity Self-driving Car Engineer Nanodegree Program.
Udacity の自動運転車のエンジニア向け Nanodegree プログラムを無事修了しました
Hey, David.
やあ デイビッド
Rahim Kenan, I haven't seen you since sensor fusion.
Rahim Kenan センサー フュージョン以来 お会いしていませんね
Yeah, it's good to see you again.
また お会いできてうれしいです
Realize if you stopped coming to work,
仕事に来るのをやめたら
they stop paying you.
お金は払われないですよ
No, It's cool. I've been working on other robots.
いいえ私は ほかのロボットに取り組んでいました
But this is the end of the car ND program,
車両の ND プログラムは終了しましたが
just too exciting to miss.
見逃すには惜しいプログラムです
I mean, just think about it,
少し 考えてみてください
you've honed your skills in computer vision,
コンピューター ビジョン
deep learning, sensor fusion,
ディープ ラーニング センサー フュージョン
localization, path planning, and more. That's awesome.
ローカライゼーション パス プランニングなどを学びましたそれはすばらしいことです
You've constructed controllers with Uber ATG or
Uber ATG を使ってコントローラーを構築し
localized a vehicle fused radar and lidar data,
レーダーと LIDAR データを融合した車両をローカライズして
and built a path planner with a fantastic team of engineers from Mercedes-Benz.
Mercedes-Benz の素晴らしいエンジニア チームと一緒にパス プランナーを構築しました
You deployed your code to a real self-driving car, that is fantastic.
自分のコードを実際の自動運転車に展開しました それは素晴らしいことです
They're supposed to be confetti.
紙吹雪があるはずですが
Did they cut the confetti budget?
紙吹雪の予算が削られましたか?
The confetti budget? I don't know.
紙吹雪の予算ですか?わかりません
Hey, Sebastian.
やあ セバスチャン
Ryan, David.
ライアン デイビッド
Hey, you're ready to go?
準備完了ですか?
Not yet because there's students here.
まだです 生徒がおられます
Students, this is a really,
生徒の皆さん
really sad moment for me in class because we come to the end.
クラスが終了するのは寂しいことです
I want to say a few words about Dave and Ryan and the team.
デイブ ライアンとチームの皆様について伝えたいことがあります
These guys have built the Nanodegree Program.
これらの人々が Nanodegree プログラムを準備しました
Not just the two of them, but all the people that you can see lined up right now,
2 人だけでなく 並んでいるすべての人々です
and it's been amazing,
これはすばらしいことです
I've gotten tons of positive comments.
私は多くの良いコメントをいただいています
It's become the largest self-driving car education program in the world.
これは 世界最大の自動運転車教育プログラムになりました
In fact, you teach most students in all universities combined.
実際には すべての大学の学生に教えています
Now, to you students,
生徒の皆さん
I'm sad to say goodbye,
別れは辛いものですが
but you come to the end of the program and you have done an astounding job.
みなさんはプログラムを修了し 優秀な成績を収めました
I've looked at the projects,
プロジェクトを見て
I've helped design them and base of what you documented and those are your skills,
プロジェクトの設計を援助しましたが これは文書化したものと スキルの基礎となったはずです
I'd have easily hired you into any self-driving car team ever run.
私だったら 自動運転車チームとして 皆さんを雇ったことでしょう
I've ran a few.
私は少しお手伝いしただけです
I really want you to celebrate,
Nanodegree を取得した皆さんを
to be happy that you get this Nanodegree.
心から祝福いたします
It's a major accomplishment in your life.
これは 皆さんの人生の中で大きな達成です
I want to be able to tell you go out and
皆さんには 社会に出て
change the world and make the world a better place.
世界を変え 世界をより良い場所にしてほしいと願っています
All right. Enough already, let's get out of here.
OKこれで終わりです 外に出てください
Really? Bye-bye.
本当に?さようなら
All right. I'll drive.
OK運転します
No, I'm driving.
いいえ 運転はしません
Come on David, I'd like to drive.
デイビッド 運転してみたいです
I haven't been here in five months.
5 カ月ぶりですね
I haven't seen you. I don't even know who you are anymore.
長らくお会いしませんでしたねどなたかわかりません
Come on, I've been working on other robots.
待ってください 私は ほかのロボットに取り組んでいました
It's just sort of the same thing, we're collaborators, right?
同じようなものです 私たちは共同作業者ですよね
No.
いいえ
Wait.
待ってください
Come back.
戻ってきてください
The car took Sebastian.
車が セバスチャンを運んでいきました
There's the confetti.
花吹雪です